<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Write Fantasy</string>

    <!-- ***ABOUT PAGE*** -->

    <string name="app_description">This app is a guide for writing a fantasy novel and covers some of the basics that you will need to help make your story come to life! \n</string>
    <string name="send_chapter">Feel free to send me a chapter or two from your book, and I will read them and give you some feedback! My email address is timo24apps@gmail.com.\n</string>
    <string name="rate_app"><u>Rate the app!</u></string>

    <!-- ***CHARACTER DEVELOPMENT*** -->

    <!-- Guidelines text -->
    <string name="know_characters_sub">Know Your Characters</string>
    <string name="know_characters_p1">In order to write really strong, compelling characters, you first need to know them inside and out. For example, you need to know their background. The circumstances they grew up in will influence their core values, motivations, flaws, and strengths. What kind of family did they grow up in? What kind of relationship did they have with parents or siblings? Did they have many friends? What did they do with their friends? What did they dream of doing or being when they were young? Do they still have those dreams? Have they ever been in love? Have they ever had their heart broken? \n </string>
    <string name="know_characters_p2">Think about what their personality is like. Are they the happy-go-lucky type? Or are they more reserved? Do they enjoy social interaction? Or do they prefer solitude? Do they have a temper? Is patience one of their virtues or vices? Are they selfish or selfless? Intelligent or slow? \n</string>
    <string name="know_characters_p3">If you know the answer to all of these questions for a character, then you are off to a great start! If not, then you have some work to do. Just remember that the more you know about your character, the easier it will be to write about them. \n </string>

    <string name="character_voice_sub">Character Voice</string>
    <string name="character_voice_p1">How a character speaks is important because it helps them stick in the mind of the reader. Imagine if you were to read a random passage of dialogue to someone who just finished your novel. They should be able to guess what character said it just by the style of speech they are using! This may not always be the case, but it is a good goal to strive for. A character with a unique voice will be hard to forget and will add some great flavor to your novel. \n</string>
    <string name="character_voice_p2">If you are having trouble with creating a personal voice for a character, then think about their personality and how that will affect what they say or don\'t say. An overconfident person will be more bold in their speech and may at times say things that could be offensive. On the other hand, a shy person will be very careful about what they say and will rarely, if ever, say something rude. \n</string>
    <string name="character_voice_p3">When creating a voice it can help to try certain sentence structures or perhaps specific filler words, such as,  \"like\", \"um\", \"you know\", and \"okay\". Give your character\'s voice some of these characteristics and it will go a long way in making their voice unique and recognizable. \n</string>

    <string name="avoid_stereotypes_sub">Avoid Stereotypes</string>
    <string name="avoid_stereotypes_p1">Avoid the boring, overused stereotypes because these characters are too predictable and not very fun to read about. Unless you plan on making fun of a stereotype, you should always strive to make your characters unique. \n</string>
    <string name="avoid_stereotypes_p2">A good example of a boring stereotype is the all-knowing wizard character that is so common in fantasy. If you wanted to change this character to make him more interesting, you could make him act like he is in control and always knows what to do, but in reality makes a lot of mistakes and has very limited power. Then allow this character to come to the realization that he isn\'t as useful as he once thought and watch him struggle with this harsh reality. A character like this is much more interesting to read about, and you as the writer could take his story arc in several different exciting directions! \n</string>
    <string name="avoid_stereotypes_p3">Never settle for an often used character type! Take those common characters and change their personalities, desires, weaknesses, or strengths and you will begin to see your characters become fascinating to write, and read, about! \n</string>

    <string name="growth_sub">Character Growth</string>
    <string name="growth_p1">Character growth is one of the most important elements of any novel and, if done well, can turn an average story into a great one. Who doesn\'t want that? But how do you help your characters grow and develop? Well, you need to introduce some conflict into their lives. \n </string>
    <string name="growth_p2">Your story is going to have a central conflict that will challenge and test your characters. Throughout the progression of the story you should also add additional, minor conflicts for your characters to deal with. As these conflicts are resolved one by one, each character will change in some way. Some may learn that they are capable of great feats of bravery and determination, or some may realize, to their dismay, that the conflict has brought out the worst in them. \n</string>
    <string name="growth_p3">Not every character will take the exact same path, and the result of their progression will be unique to them. This journey is really what is interesting about a story. Readers want to observe these characters go through hell and see what happens to them. They may root for some and hate others, but either way they will be engrossed in the story and that is the point. \n </string>

    <string name="introspection_sub">Reveal Characters Through Introspection</string>
    <string name="introspection_p1">Introspection is a great literary device for revealing more about a character\'s motivations and inner desires. Letting the readers in on the thoughts of a character will help them to see what your character\'s true personality is like because your character may be putting on an act in front of others in your novel. \n</string>
    <string name="introspection_p2">Moments of reflection happen in between action scenes and give the characters, as well as your readers, a moment to consider what has transpired up to that point. These moments should not drag on but don\'t be scared to spend time on them either. \n</string>

    <string name="action_sub">Reveal Characters Through Their Actions</string>
    <string name="action_p1">While introspection is a great way to share more about your characters, you don\'t want to always be examining their thoughts. Putting your characters in situations where they have to act can reveal a lot about them and can be more interesting to the reader. Do your best to SHOW the reader what a character is like instead of always telling them. \n</string>

    <string name="stay_in_character_sub">Stay in Character</string>
    <string name="stay_in_character_p1">Try to avoid complete 180\'s with your characters. What does that mean? It means that if you portray a character in a certain way throughout the whole book and then in one scene have them do something completely out of character, then there had better be a good reason for it. \n</string>
    <string name="stay_in_character_p2">Let\'s try an example. If your hero Roderick is normally a very pleasant and kind man but out of nowhere makes a nasty comment about his good friend Pilorus, then your reader will be confused. What is going on with Roderick? Is he being influenced by some evil magic? Or perhaps he is going crazy? Or maybe this isn\'t Roderick but someone impersonating him? Those would all be valid reasons for Roderick\'s behavior. \n  </string>
    <string name="stay_in_character_p3">But what if you never explained why he did what he did? This would be very jarring to your readers and could sour them on the story. Roderick the character would no longer seem authentic and neither would the story. If that happens, then you\'ve lost your readers so, do your best to stay consistent throughout the whole novel. \n</string>


    <!-- Heroes text -->
    <string name="likable_hero_sub">A Hero is Likable&#8230; Or Interesting</string>
    <string name="likable_hero_p1">Your protagonist is most likely the main figure in your story, and that means that you really need to get this character right. If your protagonist is boring or annoying, then no one will want to finish the story to see if they succeed or fail. So how do you make your hero or heroine likable and interesting? \n</string>
    <string name="likable_hero_p2">Let\'s start with making them likable. An easy way to do this is to think of all of the people that YOU like being around. Try to write down what it is about them that you like, and then give your protagonist the same traits. If you want to see what traits to AVOID giving your character, then think of people you don\'t enjoy being around and then write down the reasons why you don\'t.\n</string>
    <string name="likable_hero_p3">Now, what if your protagonist isn\'t all that likable? You better make sure that they are a really interesting character! Perhaps your character was almost killed by a backstabbing friend and is now out for revenge. Nothing will get in their way as they relentlessly track down the traitor to exact punishment. Such a character might not be the kind of person you would go to lunch with, but they are interesting to read about!\n</string>

    <string name="hero_flaws_sub">A Hero Has Flaws</string>
    <string name="hero_flaws_p1">No hero/heroine is perfect. If they were, then they would be very dull to read about! We enjoy reading about someone that we can relate to in some sense and someone who has no flaws is too far removed from our everyday experiences. Give your character a flaw that keeps getting them into trouble, like a sharp tongue or a hot temper. Or perhaps give them a flaw like prejudice and fear against a different race. \n</string>
    <string name="hero_flaws_p2">If you give your character a major flaw, then you should make sure that they either are aware of it or will be at some point in the story. Once they are aware of it, show them trying their best to overcome it. If you don\'t, then your character could become unlikable. Readers want to root for someone who wants to do what is right, even if they fail repeatedly. A protagonist that doesn\'t care is not someone we usually care about. \n </string>

    <string name="special_hero_sub">A Hero is Special</string>
    <string name="special_hero_p1">What is it about your hero/heroine that makes them special? Are they naturally gifted at fighting, or do they possess powerful magic? Are they extremely intelligent or exceptionally brave? Make sure you take some time to figure out what it is about your hero/heroine that makes them stand out from the crowd. Give the readers some confidence that the character has the potential for greatness within them. \n</string>
    <string name="special_hero_p2">Perhaps what makes your protagonist special is that they have no special abilities. They may just be an ordinary Jane or Joe who gets caught up in some grand adventure and somehow make it through danger by the slimmest of margins. If you do end up going this route, you might consider having your character discover along the journey that they do in fact possess some special qualities that they can rely on. \n</string>

    <string name="change_hero_sub">A Hero Needs to Change</string>
    <string name="change_hero_p1">A protagonist needs to experience some kind of growth or deterioration as the story progresses. If they are essentially the same person they were at the beginning of the journey, then what was the point? Your audience wants to read about an evolving character, so you should give it to them. \n</string>
    <string name="change_hero_p2">So what do you do to your character to make them change? One really effective method is to push their pressure points. You, as the author, know every weak spot your protagonist has, and you should definitely take advantage of that. For example, if your character used to be a heavy drinker but is now sober, you could write a scene where your character gets caught in the middle of a celebration with free drinks available. Your character will struggle to resist and might even give in and drink the night away, only to wake up in the morning and sadly realize they gave in to their weakness again. Your hero/heroine will probably recover and come back stronger than ever because of the moment of weakness, but even if they don\'t, it is interesting to read about. \n</string>
    <string name="change_hero_p3">Your protagonist will face several different challenges throughout the story, and change will happen in those moments as well. Think of your protagonist as you would a muscle. The more they go through, the stronger they will become. Be careful though because a muscle pushed too far has the potential to fail. Your goal should be to push them to the edge of what they can handle and see what they do. \n </string>


    <!-- Secondary characters text -->
    <string name="secondary_types_sub">Types of Secondary Characters</string>
    <string name="secondary_types_p1">Secondary characters are a wonderful and necessary element you\'ll want to add to your story. You will have to decide how many characters are needed, but you should count on writing at least several major supporting characters as well as many more minor characters. \n </string>
    <string name="secondary_types_p2">For supporting characters there are five different character types that usually show up somewhere in a story. These five are the villain, the best friend, the mentor, the love interest, and the fool. The villain is important enough that there is a whole section dedicated to that character so I won\'t talk any more about the villain here. Of these five, the one that may need some explaining is the fool. A fool is a wise character who will tell the protagonist the things that are difficult to hear. A lot of times they are portrayed as strange or eccentric. An example of the fool would be Rafiki from the Lion King, who helps convince Simba that he needs to face his past and return to challenge his wicked uncle Scar. The rest of the types are self-explanatory, and you can examine almost any book or movie and identify which supporting character is which type. \n </string>

    <string name="secondary_support_sub">Supporting Characters Complement the Main Character</string>
    <string name="secondary_support_p1">Supporting characters are important, but don\'t forget that the story is about your main character! Thus, your supporting characters and other minor characters are going to be interacting with your main character and helping the plot move forward in some way. An exception would be the supporting character who is off having their own adventures before finally meeting up with the protagonist. If you have a lot of worldbuilding to do, then this can be an effective way to reveal more about your world without it seeming like a tangent. Remember, however, that these characters should not only enrich the general story but they should contribute to the protagonists story. \n</string>
    <string name="secondary_support_p2">How do you create a supporting character who complements your protagonist? Just think of some of the weaknesses that your protagonist has and create supporting characters who are strong in those areas. They can then be the yin to the yang of the protagonist and really help them in their journey! \n</string>

    <string name="supporting_conflict_sub">Supporting Characters can be a Source of Conflict</string>
    <string name="supporting_conflict_p1">If you remember that I am excluding the villain, who is the main source of conflict, from this section, then you may wonder how secondary characters can cause conflict. Well, the possibilities are endless. We can write in a best friend character who disagrees with your protagonist on some point and decides to try and stop them, or a love interest who feels rejected by the protagonist and decides to help the villain in an effort to exact revenge, or an older brother who is taken prisoner by the villain. \n</string>
    <string name="supporting_conflict_p2">All of these situations test your main character in different ways and force him/her to make some difficult decisions. The key is making sure that these points of conflict advance the plot of your story instead of derailing it. Everything should be building up to the climax of the story, and if it does not then you might consider changing it or taking it out altogether.\n</string>

    <string name="minor_memorable_sub">Minor Characters: Some are Memorable, Some are not</string>
    <string name="minor_memorable_p1">Some characters in your story will only show up for a page or two at the beginning and maybe one more time later on. Some may only ever show up once. Either way, you can do your best to make each character memorable, while at the same time not stressing if some aren\'t. You want to spend the bulk of your time fleshing out more important characters because they drive the story. Minor characters help to fill in your world and make it seem more realistic but rarely do much else. \n</string>
    <string name="minor_memorable_p2">Avoid giving minor characters too much description. A sentence or two will work in most cases. Try to give these characters something unique about their appearance or the way they act or talk to help them stand out. For example, you could have a pub owner that has a big droopy mustache, or a merchant with a ridiculous looking hat, or even a soldier that has a high nasally voice. Because of these oddities, your main character, and the reader, will remember these minor characters, even if they don\'t show up again for hundreds of pages. \n</string>


    <!-- Villains text -->
    <string name="villains_opposite_sub">Villains are the Opposite of the Hero</string>
    <string name="villains_opposite_p1">Quite often in literature, the villain is simply the opposite of the hero/heroine. For example, if your protagonist is brash and hotheaded, then the villain is calm and very much in control of their emotions. The contrast between the two characters helps to create a compelling conflict and makes interactions between the two more entertaining. \n </string>

    <string name="villains_complex_sub">Villains are Complex</string>
    <string name="villains_complex_p1">As tempting as it might be, do not make your villain the epitome of evil. Why not? Because it\'s boring and unrealistic. How many people have you met in your life that are absolutely 100% evil? My guess is zero. No matter how wicked someone is, you can always find some redeeming quality in their character. Even Adolf Hitler was known for being very concerned about nature and wildlife, and he went to great lengths to protect wildlife habitats within Germany. When you contrast that with the monstrous acts he committed, you realize that there is more to the man than an evil dictator. This complexity makes Hitler interesting because we wonder how someone can be so bad and yet still do good things. \n </string>
    <string name="villains_complex_p2">Give your villain some good qualities and show them in a positive light during some scenes. This will create a sharp contrast when they inevitably act upon their evil desires and whatever they do will seem even more terrible than it would have if you had portrayed them as a purely evil being. \n</string>
    <string name="villains_complex_p3">To give your villain even more depth, explore their background. Were they once a good person? Have they always had evil tendencies? What happened to them to make them so hateful? What kind of family situation did they grow up in? Allowing your reader to know the answer to some of these questions will add some intriguing layers to your villain and make them truly unforgettable! \n</string>

    <string name="villains_mighty_sub">Villains are Mighty Opponents</string>
    <string name="villains_mighty_p1">No one wants to read about an incapable villain (unless you are writing a comedy), so you need to make your villain strong, ruthless, and a serious challenge for your protagonist. There should be at least one, if not several, moments in the novel where you show your villain doing something truly despicable (preferably something that harms a character the reader cares about). These moments establish your villain as a real force to be reckoned with and help set the stage for a strong climax between them and your hero/heroine.\n</string>

    <string name="villains_motive_sub">A Villain has a Strong Motive</string>
    <string name="villains_motive_p1">What is the goal of your villain? What is the purpose behind all of the trouble that they are causing? Don\'t be tempted to explain that their wicked deeds are simply a product of their evil nature. People don\'t just randomly do bad things. They usually have a reason for their actions. Come up with a strong motivation and your character becomes that much more believable. \n </string>
    <string name="villains_motive_p2">An example of a strong motive would be a villain who was thwarted in their attempt to seize power of a kingdom and was consequently locked in a dungeon for years but has since escaped and is now seeking revenge against their captors. A different example is a villain who is seeking an ancient magical artifact that can bring their lover back to life and will stop at nothing to complete their quest. Use your imagination to come up with a good motive for your villain and then set them loose in your world. \n</string>


    <!-- ***THE WORLD*** -->

    <string name="create_world_sub">A World for your Novel</string>
    <string name="create_world_p1">One of the hallmarks of a good fantasy novel is the rich description of the world where the story takes place. This is true even if the world happens to be the one that we live on. You really need to do a good job of painting the scene in the mind of the reader to make it come alive. \n</string>
    <string name="create_world_p2">The advantage a fantasy writer has is that the reader is expecting things to be strange or different. Because of this you have a lot of flexibility when it comes to worldbuilding. Let your imagination run free and create an environment that is unforgettable! At the same time you need to remember that what you create has to make sense and be consistent. Set up some rules for your world to follow and stick to them. If the air is extremely thin in an area of your world, then your characters should tire faster while there. If the belief system of a particular nation includes shunning outsiders, then that is what you need to portray in your novel. \n</string>

    <string name="our_world_sub">Novel Set in our World</string>
    <string name="our_world_p1">If your novel is going to take place in the world that we live in, then you need to make sure that you integrate fantasy elements in a clever way. It\'s not enough to just say that most tax auditors are actually demon hunters. You have to explain how they are able to hide the fact that they spend most of their time killing hell spawn throughout the country. This can create some challenges, but if you are able to pull it off then your novel will definitely be a fun read. \n</string>

    <string name="new_world_sub">Novel Set in a New World</string>
    <string name="new_world_p1">To create an entirely new world, you will need to put in a lot of work to pull it off successfully. You need to consider what the geography/landscape looks like, what types of creatures and people live there (covered in a different section in this app), what the social structure looks like (e.g. people ruled by kings or governments, different social classes like peasants, merchants, nobility etc.), whether or not there is some sort of religion or belief system, what the economy looks like, and how advanced the technology is just to name a few things. \n</string>
    <string name="new_world_p2">If you haven\'t realized it yet this means that there will be a lot of details which require your consideration. This can be a huge undertaking but a polished, interesting world will allow the reader to really immerse themselves in your story. \n</string>

    <string name="the_details_sub">The Details are Important</string>
    <string name="the_details_p1">What you don\'t want to do is create a new world but fail to provide enough detail to the reader about what it looks like or what it feels like to live there. Such a world is not convincing or captivating, and the reader will easily lose focus and struggle to orient themselves. \n</string>
    <string name="the_details_p2">On the other hand, you should refrain from providing too much detail. Fantasy fans love learning about new worlds, but remember that you are not writing an article for a scientific journal. You\'re telling a story. If you focus too much on describing what the world is like, then the pace of your novel will seem excruciatingly slow. A good strategy for avoiding this pitfall is to explain things in bits and pieces. You probably don\'t need to dedicate entire chapters to world description, so a few paragraphs every now and then will give the reader some more information to digest and help them slowly build a picture in their mind of what things look and feel like. \n</string>

    <string name="use_senses_sub">Use the Five Senses</string>
    <string name="use_senses_p1">Remember to use the five senses to clearly reveal your world. Describe the colors and textures of objects. Have one of your characters interact with different elements and describe what they are experiencing, either through dialogue or introspection. The more real you can make the world seem, the easier it will be for your reader to suspend their disbelief and really get into the story. \n</string>


    <!-- ***THE MAGIC*** -->

    <string name="magic_world_sub">A World with Magic</string>
    <string name="magic_world_p1">Magic is one of the most enjoyable parts of a fantasy novel. It adds a completely new dimension to storytelling that can lead to some epic tales. Magic can also ruin a story if used poorly, so you need to be careful. However, if the basic guidelines in this section are followed then you should be okay. \n </string>

    <string name="magic_rules_sub">Magic has Rules</string>
    <string name="magic_rules_p1">Magic needs to make some sort of sense even if it is not grounded in reality. This means that your magic needs to be explained somewhat. There have to be some rules, and they need to be followed! If a character is unable to accomplish some task with magic in one instance, and then, later on in the story, is able to use the magic to perform a similar task, then the reader is going to pick up on the inconsistency. \n</string>
    <string name="magic_rules_p2">Here are some questions to consider when thinking of how to integrate magic into your story: How does the magic work? Are there only certain people who can use it? If so, what are the requirements for having the ability? Does the magic need an energy source in order to work? Is the bearer of the magic the energy source or is it something external? What are the limitations for the magic? What is possible for a magic bearer? Are there different types of magic which grant different abilities? Are there magical objects in your world? \n</string>
    <string name="magic_rules_p3">Some of your readers will want to know the answers to all of those question, while others won\'t care as much. Either way, you need to give the subject some thought. If magic is only a small part of your novel, then you can probably get away with only answering a couple of those question, but if magic is going to play a big role, then you will have some explaining to do. \n</string>

    <string name="magic_history_sub">The History of Magic</string>
    <string name="magic_history_p1">It won\'t always be necessary to give a history of magic in your world, but it can help readers get immersed in your world. If you wish to include it, then describe how magic has affected the affairs of your world throughout its history. If it had a beginning, then you might include a legend regarding its genesis. Don\'t share too much information if it doesn\'t help much with the plot but give enough to give a sense of realism to your novel. \n</string>

    <string name="magic_storyline_sub">Magic that Helps Rather then Harms the Storyline</string>
    <string name="magic_storyline_p1">While magic itself is really cool, it shouldn\'t distract from the storyline. The point of the story isn\'t to explain your unique magic system and all of its intricacies. The point is to tell a story about your characters. If you find that you are getting so wrapped up in the magic that the main story arc is getting stalled, then tone it down with the magic. Mesh it with your character\'s storylines to enhance or help their journey. Magic by itself can also introduce some conflict into your story. Whatever you do, just be smart with your use of it. \n</string>


    <!-- ***CREATURES AND RACES*** -->

    <string name="world_creatures_sub">Creatures in Your World</string>
    <string name="world_creatures_p1">Interesting creatures can add both richness and depth to your novel, so you should definitely try to implement them into your fantasy world! \n</string>
    <string name="world_creatures_p2">When incorporating creatures into the novel\'s world, most fantasy writers typically use real animals that we are familiar with (e.g. horses, cattle, dogs, etc.) mixed with typical fantasy creatures (e.g. dragons, unicorns, manticores, etc.) from mythology. The advantage of doing it this way is that most of your creatures won\'t need a lot of description and are therefore much easier for your readers to visualize. For instance, if one of your characters owns a cat then you don\'t need to describe what a cat looks like or what normal cat behavior is because your readers already know that. The most you\'ll have to describe is the color and maybe the size. If you\'re already feeling overwhelmed from all of the other aspects of worldbuilding you have to focus on, then using well-known creatures can help lighten the load. \n </string>
    <string name="world_creatures_p3">The other option you have is to create all new creatures from your imagination. This can be really challenging but also really fun. The challenge will be in helping your readers to effectively visualize your creatures. If you can\'t do this, then the creatures will become more of a distraction than anything and that is not what you want. If you decide to go this route, then you need to pay attention to a lot of details like how things look, feel, smell, act, where they live, whether they are domesticated or not, whether they are dangerous or not, etc. You may not describe all of these things to your readers, but it is a good idea to know them anyway because it helps you better understand the world that you are trying to describe. Adding some of these details to your creature descriptions will go a long way in helping the reader make a mental picture of the creatures. \n</string>

    <string name="world_races_sub">Races in Your World</string>
    <string name="world_races_p1">Deciding which races to put in your novel is similar to the process of putting new creatures in. You can use all of the races of people that are found on earth (e.g. white, black, asian, etc.) as well as adding some well-known fantasy races (e.g. elves, dwarfs, goblins, etc.) or you can make up your own unique races. There are pros and cons to each so you have to decide what works for you and the world that you are creating. Again, if you are going to make up your own races then you need to make sure to have as many details about each race as you can in your head before putting them in the story. Every detail may not be needed, but it is really hard to write clearly on something that you don\'t know very much about. \n</string>
    <string name="world_races_p2">With each race in your world, there will come a long history that will involve interactions with the other races in your world. Figure out what that history is because that will shape how certain characters interact with each other. For example, if the elves in your story used to be enslaved by a different race, then there will definitely be some tension when characters from each race come into contact with each other. Be creative with this history because it can add some really interesting motivations or prejudices to your characters. If you find this hard to do, just study the history of your own nation and you will find plenty of examples of interesting relationships between nations and races. \n</string>


    <!-- ***STORY DEVELOPMENT*** -->

    <!-- How to start text -->
    <string name="tagline_sub">Start With a Tagline</string>
    <string name="tagline_p1">A good place to start when creating an idea for a story is to come up with a good tagline. A tagline is a short sentence that describes what a story is about and really grabs your attention. If your tagline is boring, then your story likely isn\'t all that interesting, and you should come up with a new idea or tweak the one that you have. \n  </string>
    <string name="tagline_p2">An example of a bad tagline would be something like, \"The son of a king sets off to kill a dragon to prove his bravery.\" Does that sound like a story that you want to read? Probably not. It sounds like a pretty dull story to me, and I wouldn\'t even be tempted to open the cover of a book with that description. HOwever, we could change that tagline and make it more interesting. Suppose it went something like, \"The reviled son of a king sets out to accomplish what his father has failed to do; slay the black dragon that is destroying the kingdom.\" That sounds much more intriguing, and you could definitely make a good story based off of that tagline. \n </string>

    <string name="start_writing_sub">Start Writing</string>
    <string name="start_writing_p1">Now that you have a basic tagline, it is time to start writing. Without thinking too much about it, write down a two page summary of your story. Once you have finished, then read through what you have written and determine whether or not the story idea is something that you want to pursue. If it still sounds interesting to you, then great, but if not, then determine whether or not you can tweak the idea to make it better. If you can\'t, then make a new tagline and repeat this process until you have an idea that you really like. \n </string>
    <string name="start_writing_p2">If you liked your two page summary, then start fleshing out your main character. The story is about them so you need to take some time to figure out who they are. Once you have a better idea of what your main character is like, then write a chapter or two about them. If you still like what you have written, great! If not, then keep trying until you get a couple of chapters that you like. If you have reached that point, then congratulations! You now have the beginning of your fantasy novel, and you are ready to start thinking about the structure of the story! \n</string>


    <!-- Story Structure -->
    <string name="basic_structure_sub">The Basic Structure of a Novel</string>
    <string name="basic_structure_p1">Most novels are written using something called the three act structure. This structure is popular in part because it is very simple; there is a distinct beginning, middle, and end. But even though it is simple, it still leaves plenty of wiggle room for the author to take the narrative in creative directions. \n </string>
    <string name="basic_structure_p2">The first act is the beginning of the narrative and sets the stage for the rest of the story by introducing the main character, the major supporting characters, the setting, the main conflict, and the goal of the protagonist. \n</string>
    <string name="basic_structure_p3">The second act is the middle section and is normally the longest part of the story. In this act the protagonist encounters different problems and overcomes several small crises as the overall tension of the book slowly builds towards the final climax. \n</string>
    <string name="basic_structure_p4">The third act takes place after the climax and is where the story winds down to a finish. During this act, all questions are answered, and any loose ends are tied up. Try to make this section as short as possible because readers won\'t want to stick around long after the climax has finished. \n</string>

    <string name="beginning_hook_sub">Hook Your Readers in the Beginning</string>
    <string name="beginning_hook_p1">If your readers have to wait until the middle of the book for things to get interesting, then you won\'t have many readers. Hook your audience in the first few pages, or at least in the first couple of chapters. Don\'t spend too much time introducing characters and setting because you can reveal more about both as the story moves along. \n</string>
    <string name="beginning_hook_p2">An easy way to jump-start the story is to introduce the central conflict or villain early on. Bring your main character face to face with this conflict and thrust them into the adventure. \n</string>

    <string name="climax_sub">The Climax</string>
    <string name="climax_p1">The climax is the point of highest tension in your book, and it should take place at the end of the story. This is the moment that your story has been building up to and what your reader has been eagerly awaiting. Make the climax as intense as you can, and reward the reader for their patience. Once your climax has reached a satisfying conclusion, then move on to the story resolution. \n </string>
    <string name="climax_p2">There are a few things to consider when writing your climax. The first is the setting. Where does the climax take place? Remember that you are going to raise the stakes as high as they will ever be in your story, so the setting should reflect the added tension. Perhaps have the final battle take place somewhere dangerous, for example. \n </string>
    <string name="climax_p3">Another thing to consider is the journey of your protagonist. The climax is the moment for them to face their inner fear or weakness and defeat it. Conquering this inner conflict gives them the strength to overcome the exterior conflict (e.g. the villain or main conflict of the story). Make sure that no matter how things turn out that the climax is unforgettable! \n</string>

    <!-- Point of View -->
    <string name="pov_what_sub">What is Point of View</string>
    <string name="pov_what_p1">Point of view is the narrator\'s position in relation to the story. It is essentially the lens through which the readers view and understand what goes on in the story. \n</string>

    <string name="pov_types_sub">Point of View Types</string>
    <string name="pov_types_p1">The three point of view types that I am going to focus on in this section are first-person, third-person omniscient, and third-person limited. \n</string>
    <string name="pov_types_p2">First-person is when one of your characters is telling the story and relating their experiences directly. Just imagine listening to your grandpa tell a story from his youth. He\'d probably say something like, \"I hated school, and I always snuck off to play a game of cards with my best friend Hammond.\" That is what first-person point of view sounds like. Note that you will be using pronouns like, \"I\", \"me\", \"we\", \"myself\", etc. \n</string>
    <string name="pov_types_p3">Third-person omniscient is when the narrator (who is not one of the characters in the book) knows everything that anyone is feeling or doing in the story. This is similar to third-person limited which is when the narrator knows only the thoughts and actions of one character at one particular moment. An example of third-person would be something like \"Yelzin suddenly came to a stop, and he remembered where he had seen the guard\'s face before. <i>He\'s the mercenary from the tavern in Bathia!</i>\" If you have read modern fantasy, then this should sound familiar to you.\n </string>

    <string name="pov_tips_sub">Point of View Tips</string>
    <string name="pov_tips_p1">Before starting your novel, you should decide which POV you are going to use because the feel of your novel will change based off of what you choose. \n</string>
    <string name="pov_tips_p2">Once you choose a POV, then stick with it! It will be very confusing and surprising for your readers if the first few chapters are written in first-person, and then you suddenly switch to third-person. There are novels out there that combine different POVs, but you need to have a lot of skill and finesse to successfully pull that off. The safe route is to stick to using one for the entire novel. \n</string>
    <string name="pov_tips_p3">If you are writing in first-person, then your main character absolutely has to be interesting. Nobody wants to be stuck in the head of an annoying or dull character. Also keep in mind that readers can get tired of listening to the thoughts of the main character, so there needs to be a lot of action to shake things up.\n</string>
    <string name="pov_tips_p4">Remember also that a first-person narrator is unreliable. They see events through their eyes and interpret what they see as best they can, but they may not understand the full picture. In this case, it is up to the reader to look beyond what the narrator is saying to truly understand what is going on. \n</string>
    <string name="pov_tips_p5">When writing in third-person, avoid writing from multiple character\'s point of views in the same scene or chapter. This can quickly become confusing to the reader. Sticking with one character per chapter will work just fine in most cases and will lead to greater clarity for the audience. \n</string>


</resources>
